hi I'm Brett contras and in this video
I'm going to go over a brand new study
um it just got released in the uh
clinical biomechanics
Journal it's by a researcher named
Cambridge and he's uh I think he's one
of McGill St McGill's students and it
was an interesting study because it
looked at two exercises that we commonly
employ in strength and conditioning and
the two exercises are called the the
monster walk and the Zuma walk and it's
using a band and it
investigated um three different band
placements around the knees around the
ankles and around the for feet and it
looked at glute medius glute Maximus and
tfl Activation so I'm just going to show
you um the exercise and talk about
muscle Activation so the researchers
theorized that the more distal the band
placement the more uh muscle activation
you'd get so you can play around the
knees the ankles or the for feet and
they they theorize that You' get the
most activation at the feet the second
most activation at the ankles and then
the least activation at the knees and
anyway they were right so this is how
you
perform
a I'm going to put this around my knees
okay the way you would
perform a monster walk you just get your
knees out like like this okay get an
athletic stance and you just walk
forward and backward but you don't let
the knee C cave in so you just go
forward and backward keeping those knees
out just like
this so that's a monster walk okay this
is knee placement the way you do a Sumo
walk is you just side to side just like
this now when I do a Sumo walk you want
a q to push
through this this uh rear leg here you
don't try and reach out with this leg
push through this leg okay so just like
this all right so that's that's a Sumo
walk and this is at knee placement do
ankle
placement you're going to move the band
to right here okay so ankle placement
all right and then that's the monster
walk for the Sumo walk
okay all right and then that's ankle
placement for four foot placement you're
just going to go right up
here at the front of your
feet okay now the reason why this the
more distal the the band placement is
going to use more muscle activation is
because now when I have it around my
feet you're not even it's not just
requiring abduction there's also an
external rotation requirement um it's
pulling your feet inwards you're having
to twist outward so this is external
rotation in addition to abduction so the
researchers were right in their theory
that this uses this requires the most
muscle Activation so again here's the
monster walk
okay and you want to make sure they're
not caving inwards when they do this and
then here's the Sumo walk all
right all right so gluten medius and
glut Maximus activation is highest when
you have the bands at the forefoot
placement it's it's the second highest
when you use the ankle placement and
it's the least highest when you use the
knee placement so anyway that's good to
know and it's good to know how to cue to
push through that that rear leg you know
if you're going this way push through
this leg this way it just helps with
form a little bit and just make sure you
get a nice athletic stance you know you
don't want people looking unathletic
when they do
this anyway hope you enjoyed the video
thanks for watching